<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[jamar.io]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.jamarparris.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.jamarparris.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-01T19:13:25-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.jamarparris.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jamar Parris]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[CurrentC and misguided priorities]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.jamarparris.com/posts/2014/11/01/currentc-misguided-priorities/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-01T17:48:35-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.jamarparris.com/posts/2014/11/01/currentc-misguided-priorities</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Much has been said about <a href="http://currentc.com/" target="_blank">MCX/CurrentC</a> and it&rsquo;s attempt to block ApplePay (and other NFC based wallets like Google Wallet) from member stores, so I won&rsquo;t rethread well worn ground except to saying the following:</p>

<p>MCX (in it&rsquo;s current form) represents a terrible customer experience with significant privacy and security ramifications due to retailers capturing your <a href="https://twitter.com/hasanahmad80/status/526551322523623424" target="_blank">social security number and  drivers license</a>, plus <a href="https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2014/10/currentc-data-collected.png?w=680&h=332" target="_blank">health and medical information</a>, not to mention making you liable for any fraudulent transactions on your checking account (while themselves <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/10/29/retailer-backed-apple-pay-rival-currentc-has-been-hacked-testers-email-addresses-stolen/" target="_blank">already having been hacked</a>). We&rsquo;ve seen this story before, where incumbents create half-baked solutions in an attempt to fight off a new challenger. That always works out well right? Remember Blockbuster and their (at best) meh attempt at trying to compete with Netflix?</p>

<p>Moving on&hellip;</p>

<p>One thing not mentioned that much about MCX though, is that in my opinion, it informs on how misguided their priorities are. ApplePay does not in itself represent an existential threat to these companies. It is at most a distraction away from the much bigger looming threats out there, particularly Amazon, but also other companies like Google, Alibaba and some other company that probably doesn&rsquo;t even exist yet. Their brand and focus on user experience will make them formidable foes.</p>

<p>All of the resources, time and effort being put into MCX would be much better spent elsewhere. Instead, what we get right now is a customer unfriendly product that even before launch is building negative brand equity with a demographic that they should be doing everything to attract. It makes me wonder if they even have a chance at fighting off the more serious challenges to come.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[the best phone for jetsetters]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.jamarparris.com/posts/2014/09/16/the-best-smart-phone-for-jetsetters/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-16T23:03:49-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.jamarparris.com/posts/2014/09/16/the-best-smart-phone-for-jetsetters</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Let me begin by saying that I love travel. This year alone I&rsquo;ve been to London, Barcelona, Hong Kong, Macau and Japan internationally and San Francisco domestically. One of the biggest things that stresses me out everytime I travel is trying to figure out a seamless way to stay connected. Given this, I&rsquo;ve done quite a bit of research and this blog post details what I&rsquo;ve found.</p>

<p>The best device for international travel is the <a href='http://www.apple.com/iphone-6/' target='_blank'>new iPhone</a>. It supports <a href='http://www.apple.com/iphone/LTE/' target='_blank'>16+ LTE bands</a> meaning near ubiquitous worldwide compatability. Samsung, by comparison tailors the LTE and 3G support in their phones to each carrier and geography, meaning far less global support.</p>

<p>In terms of which carrier to choose, it gets more complex but here are 5 scenarios:</p>

<ol>
<li><p><strong>Can&rsquo;t be bothered with the hassle of getting a local SIM card in countries you visit?</strong>
Go with T-Mobile. They offer <a href='http://www.t-mobile.com/cell-phone-plans/simple-choice-international-plan-countries.html' target='_blank'>free data roaming</a> to their customers. It&rsquo;s only 2G speed but it&rsquo;s better than nothing.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Price sensitive and looking to sign a contract to keep costs down?</strong>
Go with Verizon. They&rsquo;re the only carrier whose on-contract devices come unlocked out of the box, meaning you can seek out a local SIM card and use it without fear.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Willing to pay full price for your iPhone ($649+)?</strong>
Ultimate flexability. Go with your carrier of choice. It&rsquo;ll come unlocked in all cases assuming you buy it directly from the Apple Store (note: probably not from the carriers though).</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Do you travel to China alot?</strong>
Get the Sprint model, it&rsquo;s adds 4 more LTE bands popular with China&rsquo;s biggest carriers. On the other models, you should still get decent coverage but you&rsquo;ll have fewer options in terms of local carriers.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Do you live outside the US?</strong>
Then you only have one model to choose! Go with it!</p></li>
</ol>


<p>Happy Jetsetting!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Under-Invested Millennial]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.jamarparris.com/posts/2014/07/30/the-under-invested-millennial/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-30T22:02:10-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.jamarparris.com/posts/2014/07/30/the-under-invested-millennial</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When you&rsquo;re in your 20s and 30s, saving doesn&rsquo;t sound like much fun and retirement especially can feel like this thing that&rsquo;s too far away to matter right now. I&rsquo;ve noticed a certain level of ambivalnce among people in my age group towards personal finance. Some people either ignore it entirely (very bad) or they blindly set aside money without setting goals or doing the research and follow up necessary to ensure they stay on track (better, but not by much).</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m not expecting everyone to become finance experts but I do believe everyone should take the time to learn something about financial management as it&rsquo;s something that only gets increasingly complex with age once things such as mortgages, kids and other expenses become more commonplace in our lives.</p>

<p>Things everyone in their 20s/30s should know about:</p>

<ul>
<li> 401K/IRA accounts - the hidden fees you pay, what is a Roth versus a Traditional account?</li>
<li> Credit Scores - how they impact you</li>
<li> Emergency Funds - helps with job loss and medical emergencies</li>
<li> Credit Cards - Responsible use and how they can benefit your credit score</li>
<li> Saving for other goals (travel, education)</li>
</ul>


<p>Is there alot above to take in? Yes, it can seem daunting but our generation is used to consuming (and generating) massive amounts of data each day on social media platforms such as Facebook, Twitter and Instagram.</p>

<p>Surely, we&rsquo;re up for the task, if only more people were interested.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The urgency of side projects]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.jamarparris.com/posts/2014/06/29/the-urgency-of-side-projects/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-29T20:28:22-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.jamarparris.com/posts/2014/06/29/the-urgency-of-side-projects</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I came across 2 great articles this morning. One about the <a href="http://www.fastcompany.com/3032394/hit-the-ground-running/spotifys-design-lead-on-why-side-projects-should-be-stupid" target="_blank">importance of side projects</a> and another about having a <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/85broads/2014/06/20/can-leadership-urgency-be-taught/" target="_blank">culture of leadership urgency.</a></p>

<p>It got me thinking about my own side projects and how they seem to create a sense of urgency within me. Working on my own little ideas motivates and drives me in ways that few other things can. That sense of complete ownership of something at all stages of development (including conception, design, coding and release) can lead me to work on them all weekend and spend most of my evenings outside of work hacking on them.</p>

<p>Most of these side projects aren&rsquo;t large. Their small focus makes them approachable and fun. Their size also makes it easy to start hacking away at another idea if I lose passion for the current one (i.e. it becomes less urgent). I&rsquo;m not too focused on the sunk cost in terms of time and effort because that outlay is generally minimal.</p>

<p>That being said, companies could do well to focus less on sunk costs regardless of how large an item they are. Many people understand what a sunk cost is, but few are able to make decisions without factoring them into the discussion in some way. Learning from the past is very different from being bound to it.</p>

<p>It should also come as no surprise to those who know me that most of my side projects are travel focused. I absolutely love the travel space, spending hours focusing on future trips, everything from deciding where to go, how to get a good deal and then ensuring a great in-trip experience. I can probably rattle off a list of 10-15 travel related projects that I&rsquo;d like to build over time.</p>

<p>Regardless of their small size, every project involves learning something new, whether it be researching an interesting vertical, learning to use a new design tool, developing in a new programming language or interacting with a new API. My knowledge of travel tech, iOS, Passbook, Python, NodeJS and Omnigraffle have all come from side projects.</p>

<p>Some of these projects are never updated past their initial release, some I completely shut down over time and others I maintain with small fixes here and there. Regardless of their eventual fate, with a new skill or 2 added to my toolbox each time, their impact on my knowledge and my career path is great. I hope I never lose that sense of urgency.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[own your identity]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.jamarparris.com/posts/2013/12/11/own-your-identity/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-11T08:52:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.jamarparris.com/posts/2013/12/11/own-your-identity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;d long been a believer in owning your online presence. Because of this I bought my namesake domain back in 2007 (along with some domains for my younger siblings).</p>

<p>The reason for this is simple: permanence.</p>

<p>Even if you use a popular hosting, blogging or email service behind the scenes, having that content point to a domain you control ensures that your content lives on beyond the life of any single 3rd party service provider.</p>

<p>For the $10 a year it costs to own a domain, this is more than worth it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
