<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[jamar.io]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.jamarparris.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.jamarparris.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-30T22:05:55-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.jamarparris.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jamar Parris]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The urgency of side projects]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.jamarparris.com/posts/2014/06/29/the-urgency-of-side-projects/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-29T20:28:22-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.jamarparris.com/posts/2014/06/29/the-urgency-of-side-projects</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I came across 2 great articles this morning. One about the <a href="http://www.fastcompany.com/3032394/hit-the-ground-running/spotifys-design-lead-on-why-side-projects-should-be-stupid" target="_blank">importance of side projects</a> and another about having a <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/85broads/2014/06/20/can-leadership-urgency-be-taught/" target="_blank">culture of leadership urgency.</a></p>

<p>It got me thinking about my own side projects and how they seem to create a sense of urgency within me. Working on my own little ideas motivates and drives me in ways that few other things can. That sense of complete ownership of something at all stages of development (including conception, design, coding and release) can lead me to work on them all weekend and spend most of my evenings outside of work hacking on them.</p>

<p>Most of these side projects aren&rsquo;t large. Their small focus makes them approachable and fun. Their size also makes it easy to start hacking away at another idea if I lose passion for the current one (i.e. it becomes less urgent). I&rsquo;m not too focused on the sunk cost in terms of time and effort because that outlay is generally minimal.</p>

<p>That being said, companies could do well to focus less on sunk costs regardless of how large an item they are. Many people understand what a sunk cost is, but few are able to make decisions without factoring them into the discussion in some way. Learning from the past is very different from being bound to it.</p>

<p>It should also come as no surprise to those who know me that most of my side projects are travel focused. I absolutely love the travel space, spending hours focusing on future trips, everything from deciding where to go, how to get a good deal and then ensuring a great in-trip experience. I can probably rattle off a list of 10-15 travel related projects that I&rsquo;d like to build over time.</p>

<p>Regardless of their small size, every project involves learning something new, whether it be researching an interesting vertical, learning to use a new design tool, developing in a new programming language or interacting with a new API. My knowledge of travel tech, iOS, Passbook, Python, NodeJS and Omnigraffle have all come from side projects.</p>

<p>Some of these projects are never updated past their initial release, some I completely shut down over time and others I maintain with small fixes here and there. Regardless of their eventual fate, with a new skill or 2 added to my toolbox each time, their impact on my knowledge and my career path is great. I hope I never lose that sense of urgency.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[own your identity]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.jamarparris.com/posts/2013/12/11/own-your-identity/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-11T08:52:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.jamarparris.com/posts/2013/12/11/own-your-identity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;d long been a believer in owning your online presence. Because of this I bought my namesake domain back in 2007 (along with some domains for my younger siblings).</p>

<p>The reason for this is simple: permanence.</p>

<p>Even if you use a popular hosting, blogging or email service behind the scenes, having that content point to a domain you control ensures that your content lives on beyond the life of any single 3rd party service provider.</p>

<p>For the $10 a year it costs to own a domain, this is more than worth it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
